832-247-8742 josh@j0w0.com www.j0w0.com

I am a designer and developer of interactive websites and web applications. Not only do I have an eye for design, I like to get into the details of the code and enjoy learning how things work behind the scenes. This has given me experience in both front-end and back-end web development and technologies.

Working as a web designer and developer, some of my skills include Adobe Creative Cloud/Suite, SEO-optimized HTML5, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS/CSS, jQuery, AJAX, JSON, MySQL, cURL, phpMyAdmin, Git version control, Bitbucket, Homebrew package manager for Apple, Unix/Apache web server configuration and maintenance, SSH and command line access, object-oriented programming, Twilio SMS API, Stripe payment processing API, Google Maps API, YouTube API, PrintNode API.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# **MIS Programmer/Developer**

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-Present | Austin, Texas

- Developed and designed a complete overhaul of the company's corporate WordPress website. From outlining and developing the relational content types and taxonomies for the admin side to the UI/UX design on the front-end.
- Create and manage marketing event web applications that include event registration, attendee check in, badge printing, lead tracking, online payments. These apps have increased customer retention rates and the number of leads received.
- Develop business software that helps the company's day-to-day process such as timesheets and PTO forms.
- Help maintain and regularly update the company's Intranet built with WordPress.

#### Web Developer

COMNIO | July 2016-May 2017 | Austin, Texas

- Designed and developed online registration and retail contest forms for clients using WordPress.
- Initiated the start of the company's client portal. Integrated with third-party marketing and automation services that gathered all relevant data into one web application.
- Handled data in various ways when working with WordPress or a client's remote database.

## **Digital Media Marketing Coordinator**

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

- Oversaw all email campaigns from start to finish which included product research, writing, graphics/video production,
  HTML, and contact list segmentation.
- Maintained corporate website, event landing pages, and staff Intranet.
- Created web applications and tools to assist sales and marketing.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Texas State University**

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014

## **Queens College**

National Student Exchange, Graphic Design | Flushing, New York | 2012–2013